### Contact

8870118297 (Mobile) samsonanil2265@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/samsonanil (LinkedIn)

encounteringsaviour.wordpress.com (Blog)

## Top Skills

MEMS based sensors for medical applications.

Nanosensors for medical applications.

**Biomedical Devices** 

## Languages

Tamil (Elementary)
Hindi (Native or Bilingual)
English (Full Professional)

### Certifications

Introduction to Doppler
Writing a Compelling Blog Post
Sensors and Actuators - IISc
Bangalore

CT Scanner Hardware Training.

Machine Learning for all

#### **Patents**

Prosthetic Lower Limb without Brain Interference for Amputees.

# Samson Anil

Certified Siemens Healthineer | Aspiring Biomedical Engineer Coimbatore

# Summary

An energetic, ambitious person who has developed a mature and responsible approach to any task I undertake, or situation I am presented with. As a student with three years of experience in the field of biomedical Engineering, I am excellent in working with others to achieve a certain objective on time and with excellence. My interest lies in Sensors for biomedical applications, MEMS based sensors for medical diagnosis especially in the field of cancer treatment and Medical Diagnostic and Imaging Devices.

# Experience

Siemens Healthineers Online Trainee June 2020 - Present (3 months) India

# Edggi Content Writer July 2020 - August 2020 (2 months)

Bangalore Baptist Hospital Biomedical Engineering Intern June 2019 - June 2019 (1 month)

Hebbal, Bangalore

Worked as an Intern in the Biomedical Department of Bangalore Baptist Hospital which is unit of CMC (Christian Medical College), Vellore for a period of two weeks. This internship provided me with profound knowledge in the recent advancements and cutting edge technologies used in Biomedical Field for Medical Image Diagnosis like (MRI imaging, CT imaging, X-ray Imaging and Ultrasound imaging), Major OT equipments, Catherization Lab and other departments such as Radiology, Oncology, Orthopedics and Neonatal care.

Harvard Medical School Hackathon Participant February 2019 - February 2019 (1 month)

Participated in an International Symposium on Surgical Innovations & Hackathon conducted in Karunya Institute of Technology and Sciences in collaboration with Harvard Medical School and Boston Children's Hospital. The main speakers included renowned Doctors and Professionals in Healthcare Field from around the world. Also, participants of this Hackathon included Doctors and leading healthcare professionals from around the country. Our team of 5 put forth an idea of building a mobile application especially for people in rural India for providing essential and emergency medical services where people are deprived of basic internet connectivity.

Boston Children's Hospital Hackathon Participant February 2019 - February 2019 (1 month)

Participated in an International Symposium on Surgical Innovations & Hackathon conducted in Karunya Institute of Technology and Sciences in collaboration with Harvard Medical School and Boston Children's Hospital. The main speakers included renowned Doctors and Professionals in Healthcare Field from around the world. Also, participants of this Hackathon included Doctors and leading healthcare professionals from around the country. Our team of 5 put forth an idea of building a mobile application especially for people in rural India for providing essential and emergency medical services where people are deprived of basic internet connectivity.

## Education

Karunya Institute of Technology and Sciences BTech - Bachelor of Technology, Biomedical/Medical Engineering · (2017 - 2021)

St Marys School Science Stream, CBSE - XIIth · (2016 - 2017)

St Marys School CBSE - Xth · (2014 - 2015)